ALLAN MUHWEZI

Fairfield, Iowa 52557 • 641-233-2428 <u>muhallan1@gmail.com</u> • <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/allan-muhwezi</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (Python)

Expert application engineer with 5+ years of professional experience building full stack mobile, web, and desktop applications, contributing to the complete SDLC both individually and in teams. Excellent skills in analysis, problem solving, remote work, collaboration, and communication, and a proven history of implementing over 30 personal Android and Java desktop apps which have reached over 100k users. Able to learn new technologies quickly and effectively, with existing solid skills in languages and tools like Python, Angular, React, Flask, Java, AWS, Git, SQL, Jenkins, OAuth, CI/CD, Firebase, XML, and more.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Distributed Development • SDLC Methodologies • Design Patterns • Front & Back End Components Object-Oriented Programming • Microservices • Documentation • Troubleshooting

Languages: Python, Java, Golang, PHP, Ruby

Web: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, Material UI, WordPress, Drupal, Bootstrap, jQuery, XML

Web Services: REST, Consul

Web/App Servers: Tomcat, Gunicorn, Tornado, Werkzeug **Frameworks:** Spring (Cloud, Boot), Flask, Angular, React, Django **Databases:** MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, DynamoDB, Redis

Design Patterns: Command, Template, Visitor, Iterator, Strategy, State, Mediator, Observer, Singleton,

Composite, Factory, Decorator, Proxy, Builder, Façade, Abstract Factory

SDLC: TDD, Scrum, Agile, Kanban

Tools: Git, GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket, Kibana, Amplitude, Salesforce, JIRA, Confluence, Trello, Airtable, ZenHub, Pivotal Tracker, Slack, MS Teams, G Suite, Swagger, VS Code, PyCharm, GoLand, RubyMine,

Eclipse, NetBeans, IntelliJ, Maven, Gradle, Android Studio, RabbitMQ, Docker

Platforms: Mac OS, Windows, Linux, Android, Vagrant, AWS

Big Data: Kafka, Elasticsearch

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CAREER NOTE: Completed on-campus studies and currently taking distance education courses to complete a **Master's Degree in Computer Science** (Available for full-time, W-2 employment).

ANDELA, Kampala, Uganda • 2017-2021

Technical recruitment and training center, gathering talented technologists from across Africa.

Software Engineer

Worked remotely with 3 US-based clients, and contributing to internal Andela projects.

- Engaged in community initiatives such as TeenCode and Women-in-Tech to teach software programming concepts and share computer science knowledge with youth.
- Held internal leadership roles such as Senate member and Cohort representative.
- Contributed to internal Andela products to manage operations and support programs, such as Andela Resource Tracking, The Collective Andela Learning Map, and Bootcamp.

ALLAN MUHWEZI • Page 2 • 641-233-2428

muhallan1@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/allan-muhwezi

Client: SEESAW LEARNING, San Francisco, California • 2020-2021

Performed full stack software development using Python, Angular, and React.

- Designed new React models and added new backend APIs to create school directory, speeding student registration to classes.
- Contributed to new CSV rostering workflow, allowing school admins to work quickly and accurately.
- Maintained roster object sync which allows the support team to quickly sync in data from third party systems.
- Provided support to Salesforce integration by fixing bugs and modifications, allowing data team to collect accurate information and updates.

Client: SLING TV, American Fork, Utah • 2019-2020

Developed and maintained microservices in Python and Go as part of Content Management team.

- Made key contributions to Collection Service using Go, Elasticsearch, and Kafka to pass queries and build informational screens, ribbons, and tiles.
- Containerized Skynet microservice using Docker, preparing it for Kubernetes.
- Modified database models and wrote SQLAlchemy queries to support new functionality in Program Service.
- Added new endpoints to Promotion Service API, supporting new business requests.

Client: NIRA, San Francisco, California • 2018-2019

With backend team, helped develop over 15 integrations of online cloud services with Python.

- Translated models and API endpoints to Python from Ruby-based Naas client.
- Developed integrations which sync data with Nira from online storage services such as OneDrive, Dropbox, Evernote, Box, Asana, Confluence, Airtable, SharePoint, and others.
- Implemented different authentication methods for multiple integrated APIs.

<u>Technologies Used:</u> Python, Flask, Java, Angular, React, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, XML, Go, Ruby, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, DynamoDB, Django, Travis CI, Circle CI, Heroku, Jenkins, Git, Coveralls, Redis, Jinja2, Gunicorn, Docker, Tornado, Material UI, Elasticsearch, Kafka, Consul, Swagger, Vagrant, Algolia, Chalice, OAuth, Sentry, REST, AWS (SQS, S3, Lambda), Android

2AMBALE, Kampala, Uganda • 2016-2017

Online clothing store with both Android and web e-commerce platforms.

Software Engineer

Owned Android application as sole full stack engineer from inception to launch. Developed website.

- Developed complete 2ambale Android e-commerce app, as used by over 1,500 users.
- Implemented internal order management and delivery handling Android application.
- Integrated mobile money payments and real-time notifications.
- Provided continued maintenance of Android app after leaving the company.

Technologies Used: Java, Android, XML, PHP, AWS, Firebase, MySQL, SQLite

ALLAN MUHWEZI • Page 3 • 641-233-2428

muhallan1@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/allan-muhwezi

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Agkika Supplies (2019): Java-based desktop software used to track purchases, sales, customers, inventory, and accounts of agricultural tools. *Technologies Used: Java, SQLite*

InVacSIM (2019): Vaccination tracker app which tracks vaccinations and sends reminders via SMS. **Technologies Used:** Java, Android, MySQL, SQLite

Hillsong Lyrics (2014): Android app which displays all lyrics of songs by Hillsong music band. *Technologies Used: Java, Android, SQLite*

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Lecrae Discography, MIU (2022): Designed and implemented both backend and frontend of a MEAN stack web app which records and displays the albums and songs of artist Lecrae Moore. <u>Technologies Used:</u> Node, Express, Angular, MongoDB

Web Shop, MIU (2022): With a group of 4, developed a system comprised of 4 microservices which allow customers to add products to cart and checkout orders. Used Spring Cloud tools to architect a scalable and resilient system. <u>**Technologies Used:**</u> Java, Spring (Cloud, Boot), Kafka, MongoDB, CQRS, Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana

FinCo Framework, MIU (2022): In a team of 3, designed and developed 2 connected applications for Bank and Credit Card. Identified common features and grouped into a single customizable framework which manages customers, accounts, and payments. <u>Technologies Used:</u> Java Swing, JSON, Design Patterns (Strategy, Command, Abstract Factory, Role)

Library Management System, MIU (2021): Worked as a group of 3 to design and implement a system for libraries which supports login, adding members, managing books and book copies, and book checkout. **Technologies Used:** JavaFX, XML

EDUCATION

(In progress via distance education; expected completion June 2024)

Maharishi International University – Fairfield, Iowa

Key Courses: Advanced Software Development; Software Architecture; Algorithms; Modern Web Applications; Modern Programming Practices

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering (2016)
Makerere University – Kampala, Uganda